## Mark Gowen

Des Moines, Iowa | 319-325-6877 | mark.gowen78@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio/Website

## FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Experienced in React, TailwindCSS, Next.js, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in photography, sales, and renewable energy. Possess strong skills in creativity and project management that help ecommerce companies reach and convert new and existing customers.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Ruby, Rails, Photoshop, Lightroom, Illustrator

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Airbnb Clone - Github | Demo

A clone of the popular property booking website Airbnb.

- Improved page load time by 40% using Next.js's server-side rendering capabilities.
- Accelerated query response time by 20% using Prisma's type-safe database access and query builder.
- Reduced dev time by 30% by implementing TailwindCSS's utility-first approach for consistent & reusable UI design.

#### Belay - Github | Demo

Frontend showcase for a website that allows climbers to locate and share routes with other climbers.

- Developed the frontend using React to create reusable UI components and manage state effectively.
- Utilized JavaScript to enhance interactivity and functionality, and integrating with third-party APIs.
- Implemented with Material UI's pre-built React components, providing a consistent & visually appealing UI.

## Verbatim - Github | Demo

A simple and minimalistic design for a dictionary application.

- Utilized JavaScript to implement functionality, integrating with third-party APIs, handling user interactions, and managing the application's state.
- Implemented the structure and layout of the user interface with HTML, creating a foundation for the app design.
- Styled user interface using CSS, creating a modern and visually appealing design that enhances user experience.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Slingshot, Inc.

Des Moines, IA

Web Developer

05/2023 - Present

 Collaborate with cross-functional teams to launch websites on WordPress, with a goal to increase sales by 25% and improve conversion rates. Including SEO best practices.

Mark Gowen, LLC. Eugene, OR

Owner / Photographer

02/2018 - Present

- Developed and executed creative concepts for 100+ wedding and 50+ portrait photography clients, resulting in a unique and personalized experience.
- Collaborated with 3-5 vendors and event planners per wedding to ensure seamless coordination of events, resulting
  in a stress-free and enjoyable experience for clients.

1 Source Solar
Ankeny, IA

*Director of Sales* 11/17 - 02/18

- Implemented innovative sales techniques and training programs that increased the effectiveness and productivity of the sales team, resulting in a 30% increase in the number of successful deals closed.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including engineering and installation teams, to ensure seamless delivery
  of solar solutions to achieve 95% customer satisfaction.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Flatiron School**

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

10/2022 - 02/2023